mcdonalds.ca 2018-12-21

# Privacy Policy | McDonald’s Canada

At McDonald's®, we strongly believe in protecting the privacy of the personal information that we obtain for business purposes about our customers. To that end, we have established our Privacy Policy. In addition, we have developed Privacy Principles to guide us in the interpretation and application of our Privacy Policy. We also have Website Privacy Guidelines to protect the privacy of visitors to our website on [mcdonalds.ca](http://www.mcdonalds.ca/).  

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding privacy, please contact the McDonald's Privacy Manager.

## Privacy Policy 

At McDonald's, we strongly believe in protecting the privacy of the personal information that we obtain for business purposes about our customers, employees, franchisees, suppliers and other entities. Also, we value the trust that is placed on us to responsibly manage the personal information that we obtain.

To that end, we have established Privacy Guidelines to assist us in protecting the privacy of employee and non-employee personal information. We have also established a set of Employee Privacy Principles and Non-Employee Privacy Principles. These Principles provide guidance to us with respect to our application of these Guidelines and our treatment of personal information.

These Guidelines and the accompanying Principles are designed to assist us in fairly and effectively managing personal information with regard to collection, use, disclosure, retention, accuracy and security. In that regard, all of our employees who handle personal information are required to comply with these Guidelines and our Principles.

We are committed to following these Guidelines and our Principles. We are further committed to complying with any privacy laws that may apply to the personal information that we may obtain.

We encourage our customers, the general public and others to learn more about our Privacy Guidelines by visiting our website - mcdonalds.ca; speak with a McDonald's manager; or, contact the McDonald's person responsible for privacy issues. We encourage our employees to learn more about our Privacy Guidelines by visiting McWeb or speaking with a manager.  
From time to time these Guidelines and our Principles may be amended to address the changing needs of our business and/or changes in applicable privacy laws.

## Website Privacy Guidelines

**Information about our Privacy Guidelines and Internet Usage**  
On our websites, we may offer features, like games and colouring books, which do not require a child to provide any personal information. We collect only limited personal information from children 12 and under (like their email addresses) to respond to their online requests. For example, we may collect a child's email address in order to send the child a screen saver, but we promptly delete the email address from our system. Or, we may collect a child's email address in order to enter the child in a contest. We may also ask a child to provide an email address of a parent so we can notify the parent to seek consent. We will not collect more detailed information from a child 12 and younger, such as a postal address or a telephone number, without the consent of a parent or guardian. McDonald's will not condition a child's participation in any online activity on the child's disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in that activity.

Personal information collected from children is used solely by McDonald's or other entities that provide technical, fulfillment or other services to McDonald's. For example, such entities may provide services, such as improving our websites, fulfilling requests or administering contests. Personal information collected from children is not sold or transferred to third parties.  
We urge parents to regularly monitor and supervise their children's online activities. In order to review any personal information we have about your child or to ask us to delete that information or to stop further use of the information, please contact us.

**Links to Other Websites**  
We may offer links to websites that are not operated by McDonald's Restaurants of Canada Limited. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of other companies. If you visit one of these linked websites, you should review their privacy and other policies.

## Ten Privacy Principles to be Applied to Non-Employee Information

**Principle #1**  
We are accountable for the personal information that we collect about you.  
We are committed to ensuring that we comply with our Privacy Guidelines and these Privacy Principles whenever McDonald's, or other entities acting on behalf of McDonald's, collect and, or use your personal information.

**Principle #2**  
We will identify the purposes before collecting your information.  
We only collect personal information for purposes directly associated with our business activities. For example, we only collect personal information from customers when they volunteer their information in the following types of situations: to enter a contest or participate in a promotion; to send us a comment about our business; or to respond to a question or concern. Before we collect any personal information, we will explain the reasons for collecting it.

**Principle #3**  
We require your knowledge and consent to collect, use and or, disclose your personal information.

We only collect and use your personal information with your knowledge and consent, except in limited and specific circumstances, and as permitted by law. For example, we reserve the right to collect, use or disclose any information as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal responsibility; to protect our legitimate business interests; to fulfill your requests; or to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on a matter of public safety.  
Except in such specific circumstances, you may withdraw your consent to our use of your personal information at any time.

**Principle #4**  
We only collect information necessary for identified purposes.

We will only collect information necessary to meet an identified purpose. We will collect this information lawfully and fairly. For example, if you enter a contest, we need your name and other contact information so that we may contact you if necessary. Further, we may require additional information to verify a winning entry.

**Principle #5**  
We will limit how we use and or, disclose your information.

If we do collect any personal information from you, we will use it only for its identified purposes. We will not disclose it without your knowledge other than to our agents and/or other entities acting on our behalf. We retain personal information only as long as necessary to meet the identified purpose(s).

Personal information that is no longer required for a purpose will be destroyed or made anonymous. Occasionally, with your permission, we will send marketing information to you, such as discount coupons, information about new product offerings, etc. If you do not consent to receive such materials, we will not send them to you.

In the course of managing business operations, McDonald's may share personal information with other entities such as professional advisors, suppliers, franchisees, or agencies. Any entity with which we share personal information is required to comply with these Guidelines.

Other entities may be engaged by McDonald's to perform a variety of functions, such as fulfilling orders, assisting with promotions, or providing technical services for our web sites and information technology systems. These entities may have access to personal information, if needed, to perform such functions. However, these entities may only use such personal information for the purpose of performing that function for which the information was provided, and may not use it for any other purpose.

McDonald's does not sell, transfer or disclose personal information to entities outside the McDonald's system. However, with your permission, we may, on occasion send marketing information on behalf of one of our promotional partners ("partners") about products or services they provide that may be of interest to you. You may be asked if you wish to receive marketing materials from our partners. If you elect to receive such materials, McDonald's will not share your personal information with such partners but rather will send a mailing or email on their behalf.

McDonald's reserves the right to use or disclose any information as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request, to protect legitimate business interests, to fulfill your requests, or to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on a matter of public safety.

**Principle #6**  
We will seek to use information that is as accurate as possible.

Generally, we only collect personal information that is directly supplied by you. In such cases, we will take care to enter your data correctly, but will typically not make any further effort to verify its accuracy or update it. For example, if you provide us with a phone number to contact us, we will assume it is correct.

**Principle #7**  
We will keep your personal information secure.

We protect all personal information collected and held by us. We have implemented safeguards to prevent loss or theft, unauthorized access, use, disclosure, copying or modification. In the event that we transfer or disclose personal information to another entity, we require that entity to comply with the principles set out in these Principles and our Privacy Guidelines.

**Principle #8**  
We will be open about our policies and practices.

Specific information that we will make available to you includes how to gain access to your personal information held by us, including a general account of its use, general information about our Privacy Guidelines and how to contact our Privacy Manager. Our Privacy Guidelines and Privacy Principles may be viewed on McWeb.

**Principle #9**  
You have a right to access your personal information.

We recognize that, under these Guidelines and under certain laws, you may have a right to access your personal information. In that regard, an access request must be made in writing and must be delivered o the Privacy Manager, as follows:

Private and Confidential  
Privacy Manager,  
McDonald's Restaurants of Canada Limited  
2 McDonald's Place, Toronto, ON  
M3C 3L4  
Fax: (416) 446-3429  
Email: [privacymanager@ca.mcd.com](mailto:privacymanager@ca.mcd.com)

**Principle #10**  
You have a right to challenge our compliance.

If for any reason, you are concerned about our compliance with these Privacy Guidelines, we encourage you to contact our Privacy Manager.

**Privacy Manager**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding privacy, please contact the McDonald's Privacy Manager at:

Private and Confidential  
Privacy Manager  
McDonald's Restaurants of Canada Limited  
McDonald's Place Toronto, ON M3C 3L4  
Fax: 416-446-3429
